<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Edward Atkin's Blog</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/blog</link>
<description>I am starting a blog to write about pointless anecdotes, mundane things and random musings. It will have some pictures. I hope you like it.</description>
<atom:link href="https://eatkin.neocities.org/rss/blog_feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 12:02:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>In Which I Choke Under Extreme Pressure</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/August/stress.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1>08/08/2023</h1>
<h1>In Which I Choke Under Extreme Pressure</h1>
<p>If you have spent any time on this website, you may know that I quite like coding.</p>
<p>How much do I like it? Well I'm soon going to hit the top 0.5% of users on Codewars for problems solved. It's like a recreational activity for me (<a href="/txt/blog/2023/July/burnout.html">apart from when experiencing severe burnout</a>).</p>
<p>When an opportunity to participate in a coding tournament arose as part of the data science bootcamp I'm attending, I was so excited.</p>
<p>The moment came and the first two problems I solved with no issues. Infact, I was the first person to solve both of them.</p>
<p>This high standard of performance I set no doubt added to the ever mounting pressure I was feeling.</p>
<p>The third problem was to count how many vowels are in a string. Easy. Within a few seconds I typed out:</p>
<p><code>return len([c for c in str if c in 'aeiou'])</code></p>
<p>Wait it doesn't work, why doesn't it work?</p>
<p>Well the answer is obvious now. I'm not checking for uppercase vowels. One class method away from passing.</p>
<p>At the time I was feeling some sort of intense pressure to perform. People were talking in the background, there was an audio echo so everything people were saying was repeated 12 times.</p>
<p>The performance anxiety I was experiencing was very extreme. My hands were shaking, I was sweating and my heart was pounding.</p>
<p>I was in an unfamiliar programming environment, I didn't feel I had the time to properly read and diagnose the error being given. All this lead to more stress, and even less ability to think. I was eliminated at round 3.</p>
<p><img alt="Staring at a laptop screen with head in hands" src="/images/blog/2023/stress.png"/></p>
<p>I could have made it to the end, I knew how to solve the problems with relative ease, but in the moment I just (metaphorically) died.</p>
<h2>The Desire to Succeed</h2>
<p>Sometimes I feel there is a huge sense of competition and drive to be the best at things. This is perfectly incapsulated in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cISYzA36-ZY">a scene in American Psycho</a> where a group of coworkers compare business cards.</p>
<p>This satirises the absurd lengths for which some people will go to prove their worth, with Patrick Bateman showing discomfort at somebody having a better business card than him. On the outside he must pretend that it's all okay. Showing jealousy would be a sign of weakness.</p>
<p>I recognise this need to strive for perfection as an unhealthy trait, but it feels so deeply ingrained inside of me that it's not trivial to just think "I'm not going to be like that anymore".</p>
<p>It has lead to further struggles in my personal development, where if something is hard, often I would consider it not worth bothering.</p>
<p>This leads to a tendancy to think I'm not good at things. This is what's lead to me having my guitar largely unused for 16 years, amongst other things. The reality is that you cannot be good at things without working for it.</p>
<p>I have put effort into reframing this in recent years. Being bad at something is one step towards becoming good. If something is too hard, take a step back, try something easier, try break a task down into small steps to make it seem less daunting.</p>
<h2>So What Can I Do About It?</h2>
<p>My reaction to working under pressure was extreme. Very extreme. It reminds me of the anxiety I felt when I first tried to record my own voice. But experience let that fade, and now I only feel mildly anxious when I record myself.</p>
<p>What this indicates is that practise and exposure is key. Working under pressure by simulating stressful conditions might be the answer I'm looking for.</p>
<p>Websites like Hackerrank have interview preparation - solving coding problems with a timer ticking away. Even this has lead me to flounder under pressure.</p>
<p>Instead of using this as a learning experience, I have since avoided solving problems under time pressure, because I found it such a miserable experience. But it's time to face this head on instead of staying in the relative comforts of the familiar Codewars.</p>
<p>It's also important to practise some sort of self compassion. As humans we are flawed, we cannot perform at our best at all times, and we need to accept that that's okay, rather than wallowing in emotional agony. You can be happy with your own performance.</p>
<p>I play my dusty old neglected guitar now. I'm not good, and I'll probably never be great, but I have instead learnt to enjoy the process of learning and playing. Making small steps of progress can be the drive you need to continue.</p>
<p>Of course, I can write about this all day, the hard part is going to be facing my performance anxiety head on.</p>
]]></description>
<guid>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/August/stress.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 12:02:19 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward Atkin</dc:creator></item>
<item>
<title>On the Dusty Drawers Full of Abandoned Hobbies</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/July/dustydrawers.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1>29/07/2023</h1>
<h1>On the Dusty Drawers Full of Abandoned Hobbies</h1>
<h2>Raspberry Pis</h2>
<p>Raspberry Pis are pretty cool aren't they? An all in one computer with a GPIO header to allow easy integration with circuitry. A great way to learn programming and electronics all in one.</p>
<p>One year I decided as a birthday treat i would order myself a Raspberry Pi 400, with good intentions to learn new things. I got some circuitry to play with and then set out doing some basic programming.</p>
<p>But now, years on, my collection of various raspberry pis and electronics components all lie dormant in a drawer gathering dust.</p>
<p>My poor Raspberry Pi Sense HAT, taken out the box to look at how cool it was, then never used.</p>
<p>My camera modules, one of which was used once, the other lying dormant.</p>
<p>The RGBW LED strips, waiting for somebody to make a cool light sequence out of.</p>
<p>The servo kit, destined to be a pen plotter, only used a few times and for nothing resembling it's envisioned end point.</p>
<h2>Abandoned Hobbies</h2>
<p>This is a common theme amongst Raspberry Pi enthusiasts, we purchase boards and components and then just don't really have the drive or creativity to do anything with them.</p>
<p>Maybe I say I don't have time, but the fact of the matter is that I just don't really think of playing with my Pis when I do have time.</p>
<p>I never used them to learn programming, I never spent more than one day on my PICO-8 game, I never used DragonRuby Toolkit (probably the only game engine with a Raspberry Pi build), I never made my LED light show synchronised to Wizards in Winter, I never made my cat cam to see what my cats get up to in the day, I never made that pen plotter.</p>
<p>I am more than capable of doing these things I just...don't.</p>
<p><img alt="A stack of sad, unused Raspberry Pis and electronics equipment" src="/images/blog/2023/hobbies.png"/></p>
<h2>The Fate of Adult Hobbies</h2>
<p>It's a lot easier to buy things with the intent of taking up a hobby than it is actually learning and practising the hobby itself.</p>
<p>Buying things is not a hobby.</p>
<p>Such is the fate of many adults trying to start something new.</p>
<p>My watercolour set I got for Christmas, only used for less than a week when I realised watercolour was hard and required a lot of dedication.</p>
<p>My stacks of plastic model kits, which I find enjoyable, albeit frustrating, but don't ever feel any drive to work on.</p>
<p>My animation books, scarcely explored.</p>
<p>And of course my Raspberry Pis.</p>
<p>It's all just lying in some drawers uselessly, being ignored.</p>
<p>The crushing reality of feeling so enthusiastic at the point of purchase, only for that enthusiasm to fade away to nothing when the time comes to actually use my things.</p>
<h2>The Flipside</h2>
<p>This is quite a doomy blog, but let's take a look at the other side of things.</p>
<p>I always loved the idea of being able to rollerskate. I thought rollerskates were really cool and would make a novel mode of transport.</p>
<p>I ordered my first pair of inline skates (second hand, incase I abandoned it like so many other things) and set going.</p>
<p>It was horrible. Unlike many adults taking up inlines in their 30s, I had never learnt to skate as a kid. My first day i stood up and was completely cemented to the spot because i didnt know how to move.</p>
<p>But somehow I pushed past all that. I found the motivation to go out at 6am so nobody would see me, and learnt to skate properly.</p>
<p>It's nearly a year on and I love it. Although I found out they are an incredibly impractical mode of transport for various reasons</p>
<p>So I ordered a surfskate to get around instead, which again sat gathering dust for a while - I did have an excuse this time because I had a bad leg injury.</p>
<p>Eventually, after about 6 months, I managed to push myself to actually learn properly on my cheap, terrible Charger-X board. If you're going to get a surfskate, do yourself a favour and get a reputable brand - they're a lot easier to use and thus you will have a much more enjoyable time.</p>
<p>I now surfskate to get around and it's immensely enjoyable, albeit incredibly tiring and I have to carry around a heavy board with me. Impractical in a different way to roller skates.</p>
<h2>Going Outside</h2>
<p><img alt="An outdoor scene" src="/images/blog/2023/outside.png"/></p>
<p>You know what I think the difference is? Why I learnt to take up something like inline skating at 30 years old, when I'm usually so scared to do something new, when I have stacks of failed attempts at hobbies?</p>
<p>Because it involves going outside to do it. If I'm trying to learn to draw, or paint, or whatever, I'm at home. There are millions of distractions at home and I can instead take the path of least resistance - sit down on the sofa and waste time on the internet.</p>
<p>If I'm going to the park to learn to skate, that's all I'm doing. There is nothing else to do. If I want to give up, I have to go home again.</p>
<p>Maybe I should take those watercolours out with me.</p>
]]></description>
<guid>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/July/dustydrawers.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 09:05:52 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward Atkin</dc:creator></item>
<item>
<title>On Bootcamp Disillusionment and Burnout</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/July/burnout.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1>23/07/2023</h1>
<h1>On Bootcamp Disillusionment and Burnout</h1>
<p>I took a major decision in my life this year and decided to join a part time Data Science bootcamp to pivot my career in a completely new direction.</p>
<p>I am currently a brewer, but I have always had an interest in coding, but I've just always really really struggled to learn programming alone.</p>
<p>This is likely turning out to be one of the best decisions of my life, because as it turns out I really love doing data science things and dealing with data, but after about 2 months of pushing to learn as much as I can, I crashed hard.</p>
<p>This is some reflections on burnout and how I feel amidst it.</p>
<h2>The Decline</h2>
<p>I was fully immersed in learning data science. I was doing supplementary reading, taking on my own personal projects, learning from courses on Udemy and Youtube, doing a completely insane amount of coding problems, making sure I fully understood every concept.</p>
<p>Then one day I sat down and thought "I don't want to do this anymore.". It was like a switch had been flipped. I had gone from being completely immersed in learning, to not wanting to do anything. I spent days wasting away, feeling guilty about not doing anything, but simultaneously not feeling able to do anything.</p>
<p>I feel like I have yet to recover from it. I struggle to focus on lectures, I struggle to focus on live code sessions. Where I used to talk and contribute, I now just stay silent and feel sad. Where I would push out my comfort zone to ask questions and get support, I now just work alone.</p>
<p><img alt="Working alone" src="/images/blog/2023/burnout.png"/></p>
<h2>Breaking Free</h2>
<p>I did have one project that partially snapped me out of my rut. A completely unguided project where we had to work on a machine learning model to predict house prices (it was a Kaggle competition). That day, I spent the best part of 12 hours working on the project, so there is some spark still there, it's just that it's hiding away within me.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, whilst this project has shifted the baseline up a little bit, I'm still feeling fried.</p>
<p>The worst thing is that when I think about these things, I feel sad. Like I've gone from doing incredibly well at everything, feeling fulfilled, to just being okay at it.</p>
<p>It's all too reminiscent of University where my first year went very well, then after that, it all went down the drain and I was unable to ever recover from my poor mental state.</p>
<h2>Anti Rewards</h2>
<p>Have you ever found that you find a song you love, you listen to it over and over again, then one day you just can't stand it anymore?</p>
<p>I found great joy in solving coding problems on Codewars. I did a completely mad amount of problems, racking up about 600 solutions in 3 months. I almost found them addictive and I hit the top 0.8% of users on the site for number of problems solved.</p>
<p>But since the crash, my brain's anti-reward system seems to find coding problems repellent. I can barely find myself able to read the problem, let alone sit down and write code.</p>
<p>Not only that, but I feel like somehow by not doing these problems, my brain is losing the ability. Right now as I'm typing this, my knowledge of SQL queries I worked so hard to practise is surely being deleted from my head.</p>
<p>Now I would love this to be an inspirational story about how I managed to break free of these feelings and am now back to my old self, but I'm not. I don't know how to break out of this state of mind, but surely merely being in this state of mind is having a negative impact, causing a negative feedback loop, making everything worse, making me feel worse. The guilt making me unable to actually do the one thing that would no doubt actually make me feel better - taking a break.</p>
<p>But perhaps, at the very least, some of this might resonate with someone else who is going through the same thing.</p>
]]></description>
<guid>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/July/burnout.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:22:50 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward Atkin</dc:creator></item>
<item>
<title>On the Wonders of RSS</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/July/onrss.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1>18/07/2023</h1>
<h1>On the Wonders of RSS</h1>
<p>I certainly spend more time than the average person complaining about how much I dislike the modern internet. And yet, here I am, still using social media, still visiting Reddit, still complaining about it.</p>
<p>Because I don't know what else to do.</p>
<p>When I was younger, I just spent all my time on GameFAQs boards. That was basically primitive social media.</p>
<p>Has it ever been any different? I just spent all my time on a certain ring of websites, never leaving, but at the time I think I was content with that.</p>
<p>Am I glorifying a past that didn't exist?</p>
<p>Well, either way, I still miss StumbleUpon helping me with internet discovery. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Sy7e-pz2c8">I made a video about it</a>. <a href="https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/February/stumbleupon">I wrote a blog about it</a>. I'm talking about it now. I just won't let it go.</p>
<p>But an ancient technology has been around for a long time, one which I haven't used until recently, and it might be what's going to save us.</p>
<p>I'm talking about RSS - Really Simple Syndication. This is, in essence, an XML file containing a website's latest updates.</p>
<p>Have you come across a blog you enjoyed? No need to bookmark it and check for updates, or subscribe to that newsletter, just follow their RSS feed.</p>
<p>Comic you enjoy? Follow it with RSS.</p>
<p>Website you like? Maybe they'll have an RSS feed. I get updates from <a href="https://www.fieggen.com/shoelace/index.htm">Ian's Shoelace Site</a> delivered to my RSS inbox every day and get a daily dose of photos of great shoelacing patterns.</p>
<h2>Getting Started with RSS</h2>
<p>This isn't actually my first time using RSS, I used it once before. A long, long time ago, to follow Garfield Minus Garfield. Setting up the feed was weird and confusing and I just had a feed on my bookmarks bar which I still had to manually check.</p>
<p>But those times are long gone, RSS readers are widespread, and make the whole process painless.</p>
<p>I personally recommend <a href="https://feedly.com/">Feedly</a>, although it only allows you to follow up to 100 feeds for free. It has nice features though. You can search for RSS feeds by topic, so you don't have to know what you want to follow in advance.</p>
<p>Once you have it set up, you can just hop onto Feedly and get a chronological list of updates from websites you follow. Website <em>you</em> want to follow. No more Reddit hivemind deciding what's popular. No more social media. No more clickbait nonsense. This is yours to control.</p>
<p><img alt="RSS is Cool" src="/images/blog/2023/rss.png"/></p>
<p>There's alternatives to Feedly of course. <a href="https://feedreader.com/">Feed Reader/Feed Reader Online</a> doesn't seem to have restrictions, but it certainly leaves something to be desired compared in terms of appearance and mobile responsiveness.</p>
<p>If you don't care about being able to take your feeds with you on your phone, you can use a desktop reader like <a href="https://www.rssowl.org/">RSS Owl</a>.</p>
<p>You can organise your feeds into folders.</p>
<p>You can export your organised list of feeds and take them wherever you want.</p>
<p>You can put Youtube channels and podcasts in your RSS Reader of choice to avoid having to even go to Youtube's homepage or check for podcast updates.</p>
<p>You can follow this <a href="https://eatkin.neocities.org/rss/blog_feed.xml">blog's updates</a> and my <a href="https://eatkin.neocities.org/rss/comic_feed.xml">comic's updates</a>.</p>
<p>RSS has been around since 1999, and I don't see it mentioned much. But it deserves more love.</p>
<p>Social media is linked to depression and misery, but I feel like part of the difficultly in leaving is simply because you don't know what other options there are.</p>
<p>RSS has turned my internet experience around. And I genuinely feel more positive for it.</p>
]]></description>
<guid>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/July/onrss.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 08:59:31 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward Atkin</dc:creator></item>
<item>
<title>In Which I Discuss Multiple Failed Attempts At Making Websites</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/June/oldwebsites.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1>20/06/2023</h1>
<h1>In Which I Discuss Multiple Failed Attempts At Making Websites</h1>
<p>This website isn't my first rodeo. Or my second. Or my third. I think it's probably my 6th or so?</p>
<p>So let's talk about some internet history that surely nobody will care about!</p>
<h2>The First Website</h2>
<p>I've been on the internet since a young age, my dad worked in IT so we were hooked up to the internet in the early 90s.</p>
<p>He decided it'd be a fun idea to make his kids a website each, and so that was my first website.</p>
<p>No trace of this website exists any longer. It was simply one page, with a photo of me and a little about me. I remember saying that my favourite website was <a href="https://3drealms.com/">3d Realms</a>, which would you believe it, is still going today!</p>
<p>3D Realms hosted a whole host of shareware games so I could fill my boots with games that I never did very well at because I was about 5 years old and terrible at playing video games.</p>
<h2>The Website I Don't Even Remember</h2>
<p>Nothing on the internet is ever deleted. Except my first website, pretty sure that's gone without a trace.</p>
<p>There is, however, a second incarnation that made it onto the internet archive (somehow). I was 12 years old.</p>
<p>Here's a tip for you, don't let a 12 year old try and make a website.</p>
<p>Made with the archaic Microsoft Frontpage, it features such wonders as "Sonic", "ratchet and clank" and "Message boards" (which didn't work because I had no idea how to make websites).</p>
<p>I have managed to dig up on very excellent sprite comic I made though, which I will share with you now. I present, "Chao Wars 2" (Chao Wars 1 wasn't archived).</p>
<p><img alt="Chao Wars 2 Comic" src="/images/blog/2023/chao_w1.jpg"/></p>
<h2>I Decide To Make Sprite Comics</h2>
<p>Sometimes when people are younger they do things they subsequently prefer to forget about, and for me it was hosting a sprite comic website. Inspired by the very terrible in hindsight <a href="https://www.angelfire.com/anime3/tms/new.html">That's My Sonic!</a>, many Sonic fans of the era thought it would be fun to make their own sprite comics. Maybe they still do, but Web 1.0 is over, and nobody will see them anymore.</p>
<p>It wasn't even just me making the comics, there were maybe 4 of us all creating what were probably terrible comics that probably nobody even looked at. Bleh. It may be a good 18 years on from then but looking back on this still gives me butterflies in my stomach.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, a lot of this stuff was actually archived and I uncovered such forgotten relics as "Jonic Heroes" which will surely have been buried forever should I not have decided to mention it here.</p>
<p>So here I present to you the final comic in the Hewligg Urobokkle series (Hewligg Urobokkle is an enemy from Megaman and I just thought the sprite looked cool so I made a comic based around him, despite having never played Megaman).</p>
<p><img alt="Hewligg Urobokkle 50" src="/images/blog/2023/hu.png"/></p>
<p>This series ended with me getting older, realising I was wasting away spending all my time on the internet, and in an emotional outburst, permanently deleting the entire website and cutting all ties with online forums.</p>
<p>But remember, nothing on the internet is ever truly deleted.</p>
<h2>I Attempt Food Blogging</h2>
<p>There's not too much in this I made some recipes, thought I'd blog about it. It was also going to be a beer blog in which I documented my quest to drink a beer from every country in the world (I failed when I got to Saudi Arabia for some reason).</p>
<p>I didn't have the stomach to write those long, sprawling, rambling blog posts that seem to be a requirement for SEO rankings and quickly realised food blogging was annoying and gave up.</p>
<p>I did actually manage quite a good go at it before getting bored though, with 14 recipes making it up.</p>
<p>Sadly, there is absolutely no trace of Food Bear left online, contradicting what I just said above about nothing on the internet ever being truly deleted. I still have the photos I took for my recipes though, and a folder called "stupid pictures". And so, here is a photo of my chin.</p>
<p><img alt="My chin" src="/images/blog/2023/chin.jpg"/></p>
<h2>I Attempt Video Game Blogging</h2>
<p>Whilst I was totally into indie game development a while ago, I decided I should start writing devlogs, and thus I created an accompanying Wordpress website.</p>
<p>I branched out into writing about indie games, along with other obscure retro games. But soon the curse of novelties wearing off got to me once again and updates became slower, until I decided not to bother anymore.</p>
<p>The thing is, blogging about video games just felt like an awkward medium for it. I had such vocal shyness that I couldn't possibly imagine getting a microphone and putting myself out there for the world to hear.</p>
<p>I actually always liked to idea of making Youtube videos, and I've been watching Youtube pretty much since it first existed, but I never could bring myself to do it.</p>
<p>Eventually, I actually pulled the trigger and bought a microphone and moved my medium to video. The first voiceover I tried to record filled me with such a heightened sense of anxiety. The thought of even recording myself, let alone having to listen back to myself and have <em>other people</em> listen to me as well, was truly too much for me.</p>
<p>It's hard to put myself in those shoes now, because recording myself just feels fine now I've done it a few times.</p>
<p>And so this was the direct precursor to my Youtube Channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@ClassicEd">Classic Ed</a> becoming a reality.</p>
<h2>This Website</h2>
<p>The previous website was a Wordpress website, and I think managing a Wordpress site somewhat contributed to my dislike of the whole Web 2.0 thing. It just felt so soulless, I hadn't put any work into it, I just banged out blogs and a backend did the rest of the work for me. I didn't feel attached to it, I didn't feel like it reflected me and I just didn't really like it.</p>
<p>And so here we are on Neocities, a place I feel harks back to the Web 1.0 days that I won't stop talking about.</p>
<p>I was introduced to Freecodecamp by my boss and tried out their frontend web development course, something I never thought I could possibly enjoy, but I gave it a good go regardless. And wouldn't you know it, I think it's alright.</p>
<p>It took a while to get to where we are today, but this website is truly something I'm happy with and proud of creating. It looks good (at least I think so), I made it by hand and it's more made for myself than anyone else.</p>
<p>And so concludes a short history of my failed websites.</p>
]]></description>
<guid>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/June/oldwebsites.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward Atkin</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
<title>In Which I Discuss My Alcoholism</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/June/alcoholism.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1>05/06/2023</h1>
<h1>In Which I Discuss My Alcoholism</h1>
<h2>An Intro To Everyday Alcoholism</h2>
<p>Often when you think of alcoholics, you think of the people who are drinking in Wetherspoons (a cheap British pub chain for the uninitiated) at 7am. You think of homeless people, or people who have lost their jobs and families. You think of people who have hit rock bottom. But alcoholics walk among us, and a lot of the time, you wouldn't even know it.</p>
<p>There is no definitive definition of what it takes to be an alcoholic, but a generally accepted principle is that, if you have ever wondered if you are an alcoholic, you probably are one.</p>
<p>Generally alcoholism starts because we want to escape from something, and obliterating our minds is the only coping mechanism we can think of. Or it can simply be a slippery slope. You drink on Friday and Saturday. Eventually you add Sunday in. You had a bad day on Monday so you have a drink to take the edge off. Then it creeps up and up until you're drinking every day.</p>
<p>It happened to me, it's happened to lots of people, it could happen to you. And alcohol's grip on your addicted brain will mean you do anything you can to justify it. Plus, let's be real here, it's embarrassing to admit you're an alcoholic. It has so many negative connatations, and it's not something you want to admit to even yourself, let alone other people.</p>
<p>But this blog isn't necessarily supposed to be about the negatives of alcoholism, it's more a reflection on the positives that I've enjoyed since I stopped drinking, and hopefully it can provide a source of inspiration to some people.</p>
<p>It feels like giving up drinking is just that, giving something up, something you <em>think</em> you enjoy.</p>
<p>But it's not. By not drinking you're actually freeing yourself. If drinking is making you miserable, then you're not giving up anything valuable.</p>
<p>If you woke up every day and threw yourself down the stairs, you wouldn't think "Oh no, I'm giving up throwing myself down the stairs, I'm going to miss it". You'd think "Thank god I'm not throwing myself down the stairs anymore".</p>
<p>2023 will be my 5th year of no alcohol and thus far, there has not been one single day that I've woken up thinking "I wish I'd had a drink last night". I suspect there never will be.</p>
<p><img alt="A drawing of a stickman falling down some stairs" src="/images/blog/2023/stairs.png"/></p>
<h2>The Positives</h2>
<h3>I've Taken Up Loads of New Hobbies</h3>
<p>Everything I used to do was accompanied by a drink. Everything. At the same time, alcohol drove my drive to do anything to zero. After even one drink I would just be sedentary for the remainder of the evening.</p>
<p>I didn't have any hobbies. I didn't do anything. I just sat around and drank. And when I tried to do anything, I couldn't commit to it. Which then made me feel bad, which made me drink more.</p>
<p>But fastforward to the present day, I now have a lot of hobbies.</p>
<p>Do you know how long I tried to play guitar for without success? 13 years. But I'm finally actually capable of putting in effort and practice to get at least a little bit better. I would even say that playing guitar is enjoyable now.</p>
<p>I've also taken up active hobbies. I go running, I go out on inline skates and recently I've taken up surfskating. These are all things I would never have done before because I would have been too hungover, or I wouldn't have felt like it, or I'd have made some excuse, or I'd just be feeling too anxious and self-conscious to go out and do something.</p>
<p>Actually I still feel self-conscious now, but because I actually get a good, undisturbed night's sleep and wake up feeling good, I can leave the house at 6am to practise things when nobody else is about.</p>
<h3>I Made A Game</h3>
<p>One thing that really hit me when I stopped drinking was just how bored I felt. It was like the only reason I found anything entertaining was because I had a drink in my hand.</p>
<p>When I was younger I used to mess around making games in Gamemaker, so I thought hey, maybe I'll give that a shot again. And I did.</p>
<p>I made a massive game called <a href="https://eatkin.itch.io/other-minds">Other Minds</a> which I dedicated two years of effort to.</p>
<p>Okay, looking back it isn't as good as I thought it was at the time, but it's still an absolutely massive accomplishment. And most importantly it laid the groundwork for my next point.</p>
<h3>I'm Actually Learning Things</h3>
<p>I made this website. Maybe that doesn't seem like much but I've never made a website before (at least, nothing that didn't look like a dumpster fire), and not for lack of trying. Infact I've tried learning programming many times before, but never really succeeded.</p>
<p>Without alcohol flowing through my veins, I've been able to actually see joy in learning. It's no longer a means to an end, I'm actually actively interested in knowing about things and how to do things. I'm not just doing it because I think I should.</p>
<p>I've always quite enjoyed programming, but struggled to get out of my comfort zone. But now I feel like I'm making real progress. I'm learning new things every day and I'm actually enjoying it. I'm always looking forward to the next thing I'm going to learn.</p>
<h3>Closing</h3>
<p>It's been a long road to get to this point. Quitting drinking isn't just flicking a switch and instantly your life is amazing. We all have things to deal with, and alcohol doesn't mean you don't have to deal with them. Drinking yourself into obliteration just means you're not dealing with them. And you're also drunk. And hungover. And miserable.</p>
<p>Quitting drinking, for me, was the first step in a long journey of self-improvement. One which I hope will continue throughout the rest of my life.</p>
<p>I write this blog for my friend who has just started his journey of sobriety.</p>
<p>Here's some good links:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/stopdrinking/">Reddit's Stop Drinking subreddit - A great, understanding community of people who want to support you</a></li>
<li><a href="https://eatkin.itch.io/beer">Beer - A bitsy game I made about drinking. You can walk around and read the narrative</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
<guid>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/June/alcoholism.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward Atkin</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
<title>In Which I Break Free From My Sister's Banana Boycott</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/April/bananas.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1>17/04/2023</h1>
<h1>In Which I Break Free From My Sister's Banana Boycott</h1>
<p>I was the younger sibling in my household, thus, I had the tendancy to copy what my older sister did.</p>
<p>I used to eat bananas, until one day, she said she hated bananas. Well, I must hate bananas too!</p>
<p>I never ate a banana again.</p>
<p>The End.</p>
<p><img alt="A really badly drawn, out of proportion banana" src="/images/blog/2023/banana.png"/></p>
<p>Actually more recently, I've been trying to get over my preconceptions of foods I don't "like". Despite never touching oranges, clementines or kiwis, I now regularly eat all of them.</p>
<p>But bananas, those were a psychological barrier that I found incredibly difficult to overcome. I've had them blended up into smoothies where you can't tell they're there, but an actual, whole banana? I couldn't do it.</p>
<p>One day, I just thought this is ridiculous. I've read enough psychology books to know that if I eat bananas, my brain will decide "Why would we eat bananas if we didn't like them?".</p>
<p>So I ate a damn banana, finally, and although my body resisted by making me feel nauseous, that banana was perfectly good.</p>
<p>Infact, now, I love bananas. I eat them all the time, they're the ideal fruit. So easy and convenient to eat. I even save the skins and cook and eat those as well.</p>
<p>Oh and by the way, my sister has been merrily eating bananas this whole time because it turns out she was just being a petulant child.</p>
<p>This is about bananas, but it's also about overcoming preconceptions. There are so many things I don't do or put off because they're scary, or it's easier to just not do them.</p>
<p>So basically I didn't eat a banana for about 25 years because somebody else said they didn't like them.</p>
<p>Just eat the damn banana.</p>
]]></description>
<guid>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/April/bananas.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward Atkin</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
<title>In Which I Reminisce About The Early Days Of The Internet</title>
<link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/February/stumbleupon.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1>22/02/2023</h1>
<h1>In Which I Reminisce About The Early Days Of The Internet</h1>
<p>Remember the internet? Back when everything was less centralised, and things looked worse.</p>
<p>I spend most of my time on Discord and Reddit now, never leaving much. It's kind of sad.</p>
<p>SEO has basically ruined everything. That's why good stuff is buried and the spammiest spam is pushed to the top of search results. That's why when you look up a recipe you have to scroll through 5 minutes of fluff that I'm not convinced anyone ever reads to actually find the recipe.</p>
<p>Let's not be too critical though, the internet is a wonderful tool. I can literally pull a phone out my pocket and look up anything I want immediately. It's a rare occassion I can't find what I'm looking for.</p>
<p>But it just doesn't feel as expressive as it used to be.</p>
<h2>Stumble Upon</h2>
<p>I made a video recently musing about <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Sy7e-pz2c8">StumbleUpon</a>, it was a discovery engine that took you to cool random websites. In modern times, with SEO spam, it's become more difficult than ever to find cool stuff.</p>
<p>It was just when we needed StumbleUpon more than ever that it was shut down, replaced by some awful service called <a href="https://mix.com/">Mix</a>. Mix seems to just send you to blogs I've just been complaining about.</p>
<p>Mix is bad. It's been almost 5 years since StumbleUpon shut down now and there's no replacement. Or maybe there is a replacement, but because of the curse of SEO, I can't find it.</p>
<p>People used to make things for the sake of it. Now there seems to be a ton of focus on monetisation. Even this website that I personally made just points you to stuff I've made, some of which requires you to pay money to access.</p>
<p><img alt="Drawing of me using StumbleUpon" src="/images/blog/2023/stumbleUpon.png"/></p>
<h2>Neocities</h2>
<p>I love Neocities, because it kind of goes against the modern internet. There's no soulless corporate Wordpress sites here. You make an account, and you're given an index.html. That's it. That's all there is. And you can really show off your personality through an amateur looking website. And it's that amateur look I miss dearly.</p>
<p>Stuff on Neocities is cool. Check out this page I found called Tesseract. <a href="https://boxy.neocities.org/tesseract">It's a page full of tesseracts</a>. </p>
<p>It doesn't try to sell you anything, it doesn't try and justify its existense, it's just a page of tesseracts. And it's for that reason that it's very memorable.</p>
<h2>The Blog's Life's Purpose</h2>
<p>So that's why I'm here, writing this. I want to write about nothing, random musings, pointless ramblings.</p>
<p>I want to remember why I make content in the first place. It's for myself, I want to talk about stuff. And it's thanks to the internet I can share stuff with the world. It's just not guaranteed that anybody will actually read it.</p>
<p>Hopefully I don't just forget about this and never write anything ever again.</p>
]]></description>
<guid>https://eatkin.neocities.org/txt/blog/2023/February/stumbleupon.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward Atkin</dc:creator>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>