<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
  <title>Pixelated Peculiarities</title>
  <link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/blog</link>
  <description>An absolute dumpster fire of a sprite comic</description>
  <item>
    <title>Commander Keen 3 Keen Must Die True Ending</title>
    <link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/comics/pages/comic_8</link>
    <description>This website isn't my first rodeo. Or my second. Or my third. I think it's probably my 6th or so? So let's talk about some internet history that surely nobody w...The Vorticons are dead and Commander Keen is happy. He is also a bit sad because he killed them.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Inspected Gadget and Kuzco the Emperor's New Groove Ride a Rollercoaster</title>
    <link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/comics/pages/comic_7</link>
    <description>Inspected Gadget and Kuzco the Emperor's New Groove ride a rollercoaster and they DO NOT die. They are both very happy.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Hewligg Urobokkle and the Mysterious Case of the Missing Pencil</title>
    <link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/comics/pages/comic_6</link>
    <description>Hewligg Urobokkle is a detective and he's trying to find a pencil but he can't find it because it's missing.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Mario and Luigi Drink England Juice</title>
    <link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/comics/pages/comic_5</link>
    <description>I'm here to make ironic sprite comics and drink England juice, and I'm all out of England juice.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Guybrush Threepwood and the Ordinary Rubber Chicken With a Pulley in the Middle of Th eK</title>
    <link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/comics/pages/comic_4</link>
    <description>Guybrush Threepwood finds a perfectly normal rurbber chicken with a pulley in the middle. OR DOES HE? (He does.) Oh, and there's a monkey. And a pirate. named LeChuck. And a ghost. nee nee noo noo</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Alex Kidd's Whacky Wheelie Adventure</title>
    <link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/comics/pages/comic_3</link>
    <description>Alex Kidd drives a car and it's whacky and wheelie.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Gotta Grow Pasta</title>
    <link>https://eatkin.neocities.org/comics/pages/comic_2</link>
    <description>Knuckles the Echidna tries to punch Sonic but it doesn't work because he's too fast, so he grows pasta.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>https://eatkin.neocities.org/comics/pages/comic_1</title>
    <link>Sonic the Hedgehog in Chilli Dog Zone</link>
    <description>Sonic the Hedgehog tells Commander Keen to have a chilli dog but finds out he doesn't know what they are, so they go to Chilli Dog Zone.</description>
  </item>
</channel>

</rss>